Fuwen TAN

CONTACT fuwen.tan@gmail.com

Summary I am a researcher working on Vision & Language, and on-device LLMs.

RESEARCH Mobile Quant: Mobile-friendly Quantization for On-device Language Models

Fuwen Tan, Royson Lee, Lukasz Dudziak, Shell Xu Hu, Sourav Bhattacharya, Georgios Tz-

https://fwtan.github.io/

imiropoulos, Timothy Hospedales, Brais Martinez

Arxiv, 2024

Effective Self-supervised Pre-training on Low-compute Networks without Distillation

Fuwen Tan, Fatemeh Saleh, Brais Martinez

International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR), 2023

iBoot: Image-bootstrapped Self-Supervised Video Representation Learning

Fatemeh Saleh, Fuwen Tan, Adrian Bulat, Georgios Tzimiropoulos, Brais Martinez

Arxiv, 2022

EdgeViTs: Competing Light-weight CNNs on Mobile Devices with Vision Transformers

Junting Pan, Adrian Bulat, **Fuwen Tan**, Xiatian Zhu, Lukasz Dudziak, Hongsheng Li, Georgios Tzimiropoulos, Brais Martinez

European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2022

Instance-level Image Retrieval using Reranking Transformers

Fuwen Tan, Jiangbo Yuan, Vicente Ordonez

International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV), 2021

Curriculum Labeling: Self-paced Pseudo-Labeling for Semi-Supervised Learning

Paola Cascante-Bonilla, Fuwen Tan, Yanjun Qi, Vicente Ordonez

AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence. (AAAI), 2021

Drill-down: Interactive Retrieval of Complex Scenes using Natural Language Queries

Fuwen Tan, Paola Cascante-Bonilla, Xiaoxiao Guo, Hui Wu, Song Feng, Vicente Ordonez

Conf. on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2019

Text2Scene: Generating Compositional Scenes from Textual Descriptions

Fuwen Tan, Song Feng, Vicente Ordonez

Conf. on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2019, Oral, Best Paper Finalist

Where and Who? Automatic Semantic-Aware Person Composition

Fuwen Tan, Crispin Bernier, Benjamin Cohen, Vicente Ordonez, Connelly Barnes

Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV), 2018

FaceCollage: A Rapidly Deployable System for Real-time Head Reconstruction for On-The-Go 3D

Telepresence

Fuwen Tan, Chi-Wing Fu, Teng Deng, Jianfei Cai, Tat Jen Cham

ACM Multimedia (ACM MM, full paper), 2017

High-Quality Kinect Depth Filtering For Real-time 3D Telepresence

Mengyao Zhao, Fuwen Tan, Chi-Wing Fu, Chi-Keung Tang, Jianfei Cai, Tat Jen Cham

Conf. on Multimedia and Expo (ICME), 2013

Field-Guided Registration for Feature-Conforming Shape Composition Hui Huang, Minglun Gong, Daniel Cohen-Or, Yaobin Ouyang, Fuwen Tan, Hao Zhang SIGGRAPH Asia, 2012

EDUCATION University of Virginia

Charlottesville, United States Ph.D. in Computer Science Aug.2015 - May.2021

Advisor: Vicente Ordóñez Román

Zhejiang University Hangzhou, China M.S.in Mathematics Sep.2010 - Jun.2012

Sun Yat-sen University Guangzhou, China B.S. in Mathematics Sep.2006 - Jun.2010

EXPERIENCE

Samsung AI Center, Cambridge, United Kingdom

June.2021 - Present

Researcher at the Future Interaction Team

R&D on Vision & Language, and on-device LLMs.

Adobe Research, College Park, United States

June.2019 - Aug.2019

Machine learning intern at the Document Intelligence Lab

Research on structured representations for multimodal document analysis.

Amazon A9, Palo Alto, United States

May.2018 - Aug.2018

Applied scientist intern at the Visual Search & AR team

Design and implement a working solution for an improved image segmentation approach for the creation of AR models.

Honda Research Institute, Mountain View, United States

May.2016 - Aug.2016

Research intern in the Perception Group

Research on applications of Deep Learning to traffic participant detection.

Nanyang Technological University, Singapore

Aug.2012 - Jul.2015

Research Associate at the BeingThere Centre, Institute for Media Innovation

Design and implement a low-cost, fast and realistic system for personal 3D telepresence.

SERVICE

Reviewer / Program Committee

ICLR, ICML, ECCV, NeurIPS, EMNLP	2024
AAAI, ICLR, PAMI, ICCV, NeurIPS	2023
ICLR, CVPR, ICML (Outstanding Reviewer), ECCV, NeurIPS	2022
AAAI, ICLR, CVPR (Outstanding Reviewer), IJCAI, ICML, ICCV, NeurIPS	2021
AAAI, CVPR, ECCV (Outstanding Reviewer), NeurIPS	2020
ICCV	2019